(upbeat music)
- Hello English learners,
welcome back to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
- And I'm Erica.
- And we're bringing you
another great elementary
lesson today, one that
takes place at the office.
- Yes, today we're gonna
teach you some great
phrases so that you can
ask people to help you.
- Right, and I think this dialogue
is with a new person at the office.
So when you're new, you always
need to ask people for favors.
- Exactly. - Yeah.
- So we're gonna be asking for a favor.
- So Marco, what exactly is a favor?
- Something that a person does for you.
- Like a small, helpful thing.
- Yeah, a small, helpful thing.
So, you know, like, can
you pass me that pencil?
Maybe that's even a favor.
- Yeah, or maybe, can you
pick me up on your way to work?
- Yeah, that's a favor.
Or even lending money to your friend.
That's a favor.
- Yeah.
- So that's what we're gonna be talking
about favors and how to ask for one.
- 'Cause you always
have to do this at work.
- At work with your
friends, with your family.
- So let's listen to the dialogue
and then we'll come back
and explain all the vocabulary.
(upbeat music)
- Um, sorry to bother you.
My name is Rachel, I'm new here.
Can I ask you for a favor?
- Hi Rachel, welcome on board.
I'm afraid I can't help you right now.
I'm getting ready for a
very important meeting.
- Excuse me, but can I
bother you for a second?
- You know what, I'd love to help you,
but I'm about to meet an important client.
Do I ask Sean instead?
At least it's right over there.
Sorry to interrupt you, Sean.
Could you do me a quick favor?
- Actually, I'm working on a document
that's doing a couple of minutes.
I really can't talk right
now, sorry about that.
- Geez, I just want to know
where the bathroom is.
What's wrong with you people?
(upbeat music)
- So a pretty busy office.
- Pretty unhelpful colleagues.
- I know everyone's so busy
they didn't help this poor girl.
- Yeah, I hope she found the bathroom.
- Now let's take a look at the
language from the dialogue.
So let's start with language takeaway.
- Language takeaway.
- There's some great language
in the dialogue, wasn't there?
- Yeah, a lot of interesting
phrases and words.
The first one that I saw
that was really interesting
is on board.
- On board.
- Welcome on board.
- Well, we've got some examples
of how this phrase is used.
So let's listen to them to help
us understand the meaning.
- Example one.
- Welcome on board, Sarah.
Do you have any questions?
Please feel free to ask me.
- Example two.
- We need to get our new office
assistant on board as soon as possible.
- Example three.
- We decided to bring Melissa on
board to join the marketing team.
- So basically it means
welcome to the company.
- Welcome to the company.
- Or the team.
- Yeah.
- Welcome on board.
- So on board is the
same as to the company.
- I guess also when you get on a
ship, they'll tell you welcome on board.
- Yes, that's where it comes from.
- Or an airplane.
- Yeah, yeah.
- Welcome on board.
Okay, let's take a look at
our next word, about two.
- About two.
- I'm about two.
- So this is a great phrase to explain
that you're about to do something.
- I'm going to do this thing really soon.
- Okay, so for example, you can
say, I'm about to go out for lunch.
Or I could say, hey, Marco,
let's go record a show.
- I'm about to go into a meeting.
- Exactly.
- Yep.
- About to.
- Going to do something really soon.
- Okay.
The next word we have is instead.
- Instead.
It means in the place of.
- In the place of.
- Yep.
- So for example, if we're at dinner,
I could say, I'll have the
chicken instead of the fish, right?
- Or I can say, I wanted to buy a
red sweater, but they didn't have one.
So I bought a blue one instead.
- Instead.
- Okay.
So in the place of.
- Yep.
- And our last word for
language takeaway, interrupt.
- Interrupt.
So when somebody
interrupts you, they come in
and they talk to you while you're doing
something or maybe while you're speaking.
- Or maybe you're busy and
people come and bother you.
- Oh, bother you.
- Yeah.
- Okay.
- So interrupt.
- Interrupt.
Okay, some great words here in our
dialogue and now we can listen to it again.
This time it's going
to be a little bit slower.
- And you'll be able to understand
the language a little bit better.
(upbeat music)
- Um, sorry to bother you.
Um, my name is Rachel.
I'm new here.
Can I ask you for a favor?
- Hi, Rachel.
Welcome onboard.
I'm afraid I can't help you right now.
I'm getting ready for a
very important meeting.
- Excuse me, but can I
bother you for a second?
You know what?
I'd love to help you, but I'm
about to meet an important client.
Do you want to try Sean instead?
He sits right over there.
- Sorry to interrupt you, Sean.
Could you do me a quick favor?
- Actually, I'm working on a document
that is due in a couple of minutes.
I really can't talk to you right now.
It's not any about that.
- Geez.
I just want to know where the bathroom is.
What's wrong with you, people?
(upbeat music)
- Okay, so there are some great ways that
you can ask someone for a favor, right?
- Yeah, we want to show you some
really useful phrases for asking for help.
- So let's start with putting it together.
- Putting it together.
- Let's listen to some different ways of
how you can ask someone for a favor.
- Example one.
May I get you to do me a favor?
Can you carry this package
in your suitcase for me?
- Example two.
Can you ask you a favor?
Can you just finish this report for me?
- Example three.
- Will you do me a favor
and pass me that file?
- Okay, so those were great
examples of asking for a favor.
In our dialogue, we
heard, can I ask you a favor?
- But we could also say, can
I get you to do me a favor?
- Right, can I get you to do me a favor?
Also, I could say, will you do me a favor?
- Will you do me a favor?
- Right.
So those are different
ways of asking for a favor.
- Let's say you want to ask
someone for a favor, right?
But they're busy, right?
So you'll need some
phrases to help you do this.
- Exactly, you need some phrases
to interrupt somebody, right?
So let's listen to
some examples of what
phrases you can use to
begin to talk to someone.
- Yeah, to interrupt them.
- Okay.
- I hate to bother you,
but I hate to bother you,
but I'm sorry to bother you,
but I don't mean to bother you,
but I don't mean to bother you, but...
- Okay, so those are
really nice and polite ways
of beginning to talk to someone.
- Exactly, they're really
useful at the office.
- So maybe you want to talk to your boss,
you knock on his door, kind of open it a
little bit and say, I'm sorry to bother you,
but I was wondering if you
have time for a meeting today.
- Or you could say, I hate to bother you,
but do you have time for a meeting today?
- Exactly.
- So those are great ways
of starting up a conversation,
and maybe setting it up
to ask for a favor, right?
So we can combine them, I could say, I hate
to bother you, but can you do me a favor?
- Perfect, right?
- Yeah, really useful.
- So then you can ask someone for a favor.
- Yeah.
- Okay, great stuff.
So I guess we can listen
to our dialogue again.
- Yeah, let's listen to our
dialogue for the third time,
and this time I'm sure you'll
understand it a lot better.
(upbeat music)
- I'm sorry to bother you, my
name is Rachel, I'm new here.
Can I ask you for a favor?
- Hi Rachel, welcome on board.
I'm afraid I can't help you right now,
I'm getting ready for a
very important meeting.
- Excuse me, but can I
bother you for a second?
You know what, I'd love to help you,
but I'm about to meet an important client.
Do I ask Sean instead?
- No, at least it's right over there.
- Sorry to interrupt you, Sean.
Could you do me a quick favor?
- Actually, I'm working on a document
that's doing a couple of minutes,
I really can't talk right
now, sorry about that.
- Jeez, I just want to know
where the bathroom is.
What's wrong with you, people?
(upbeat music)
- All right, so now you have
all the vocabulary necessary,
the next time you need
to ask someone for a favor.
- Yes.
- At the office with your
friends, with your family, anyone.
- Well everyone, we
are out of time for today,
but remember to visit our
website at EnglishPod.com.
- Exactly at our website, you'll
find the script of the dialogue,
and also you'll find intermediate lessons,
upper-intermediate, and even advanced.
- Yeah, exactly.
Our website is a great
resource for learning.
Marco and I are always there
to answer your questions,
and we also have lots of helpful
users who answer your questions.
- Exactly, so don't miss out,
come to our website at EnglishPod.
com, and we'll see you there.
- Until next time, bye.
(upbeat music)